Samuel George Morton papers LCP.Morton
Library Company of Philadelphia
- Series I. Correspondence
  - Haldeman, S. S., with extracts from letters from Say to Melsheimer, 1844 August 19; [7388 F 32] (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Martin, J. R., regarding his return from Bengal, 1844 August 30; [7388 F 33] (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - King, H., regarding the classification of fish and the state of science at St. Louis, 1844 October 7; [7388 F 34] (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Dickson, S[amuel] Henry, thanking Morton for his characteristics of the Indian race, 1844 October 20; [7388 F 35] (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Secrétaire en tour d'office de l' Académie Royale des Sciences, Shrenberg, acknowledging books received, 1844 October 30; [7388 F 36] (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - King, Alfred J., regarding fossil footprints in coal rocks, 1844 November 22, 1844 December 28; [7388 F 44] (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Dean, Amos, regarding Crania Americana, 1844 November 27; [7388 F 40] (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Wharton, Francis, 1844 December 8; [7388 F 42] (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Tefft, J. K., regarding his election as honorary member of the Georgia Historical Society, 1844 December 13, 1845 July 17; [7388 F 62] (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Harris, A. C., letter of thanks for book on Egyptian ethnography, 1844 December 18; [7388 F 43] (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Bispham, William M., regarding crania, 1844 December 18, 1845 July 22; [7388 F 64] (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Bridges, George W., 1844 December 20, 1845 October 16; [7388 F 75] (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Porter, J. M., letter of thanks, 1845 January [3]; [7388 F 46] (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Condie, D. Francis, notification of election as fellow to the College of Physicians of Philadelphia, 1845 January 13; [7388 F 45] (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Griscom, John, letter of thanks, 1845 January 14; [7388 F 47] (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Gliddon, George R., regarding lectures on Egyptology, crania, etc., 1845 February 22-1845 December 30; [7388 F 96] (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Hayward, George, letter of thanks for his work on Egyptian crania, 1845 March 22; [7388 F 49] (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Abert, J. J., regarding nomination of students for West Point Military Academy, 1845 March 22; [7388 F 39, 50] (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Reports from the University of Pennsylvania, 1845 March 31, 1845 July 2; [7388 F 59] (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Townsend, John K., regarding a Mexican skull presented by Baron von Gerolt, 1845 April 3, 1845 April 28; [7388 F 53] (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Bispham, Charles, regarding Mr. Burrough's estate, etc., 1845 April 8, 1845 October 22; [7388 F 76] (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Atlee, Washington L., introducing Peter Craig, 1845 April 15; [7388 F 51] (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Pickering, John, regarding Lepsius's letter and Egyptian museum, 1845 April 21, 1845 December 12; [7388 F 89] (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Troyer, A., regarding "une population mélanienne dans les montagnes de l'Himalya", 1845 April 27; [7388 F 52] (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Ravenel, Edmund, regarding fossils from South Carolina, 1845 April 28, 1845 June 13; [7388 F 56] (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Foster, N. A., regarding crania from South America, 1845 May 5, 1845 December 17; [7388 F 91] (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Page, Thomas S., regarding skulls from South America, presented by John Houston, 1845 May 7; [7388 F 54] (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Tuomey, M., regarding fossils from South Carolina, 1845 May 15; [7388 F 55] (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Gray, Asa, mentioning Professor von Martius, 1845 May 29, 1845 September 9, 1845 September 25, 1845 December 23; [7388 F 93] (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Bartlett, John R., regarding the American Ethnological Society, 1845 June 13, 1845 June 30, 1845 December 1, 1845 December 23; [7388 F 94] (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Bennett, John J., 1845 June 14, 1845 June 17; [7388 F 57] (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Engelmann, George, regarding Indian graveyards in the Mississippi Valley, 1845 July 1; [7388 F 58] (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Retzius, Anders, regarding research on the subject of the crania of Scandinavia, 1845 July 12; [7388 F 60] (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Miller, John S., introducing A. A. Retzuis, 1845 July 15; [7388 F 61] (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Gibbes, Robert W., regarding scientific matters, 1845 July 15, 1845 October 13; [7388 F 73] (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - [Elwyn], A. Langdon, regarding sale of fossils, 1845 July 19; [7388 F 63] (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Holmes, Francis. S., regarding fossils found on his plantation, 1845 July 21, 1845 August 11; [7388 F 67] (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Alter, B. F., regarding obtaining Indian skulls, 1845 July 22; [7388 F 65] (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Strain, [J.] G., regarding his attempt to explore in Brazil, 1845 July 23; [7388 F 38, 66] (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Silliman, Benjamin Jr., 1845 July 23, 1846 December 21, 1847 January 11; [7389 F 48] (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - McGinnes, J. H. W., regarding the Diagnothian Literary Society of Marshall College announcing his election as honorary member, 1845 August 18; [7388 F 68] (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - See, Charles A., requesting specimens of skulls, 1845 August 20, 1845 September 6; [7388 F 70] (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Pickering, Charles, requesting that Morton transmit a letter to Mr. Gliddon, 1845 September 24; [7388 F 71] (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Minor, B. B., requesting that Morton transmit a letter, 1845 September 27; [7388 F 72] (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Ogilby, William, letter of thanks from the Zoological Society of London, 1845 October 4, 1847 June; [7388 F 71] (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Baily, J. W., regarding Morton's gift to the West Point library and the skeleton of the mastodon found at New Burgh, 1845 October 6, 1845 November 1; [7388 F 80] (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - McCall, Alexander, 1845 October 14-1845 December 11, undated; [7388 F 88] (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Estes, M., regarding the origin of the human races, 1845 October 15; [7388 F 74] (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Nott, Josiah C., regarding a controversy on the origin of races of men, etc., 1844 October 15, 1845 February 20, 1845 May 19, 1845 June 1, 1845 July 15, 1845 September 4; [7388 F 69] (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - French, Benjamin F., regarding the gift of skulls from Dr. Jones and about presenting his library to New Orleans, 1845 October 18, 1847 March 19; [7389 F 59] (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Hodgson, William B., regarding Bunsen's work and Governor Hammond's slavery letters, etc., 1845 October 24, 1845 December 4; [7388 F 86] (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Cramer, C., regarding books, etc. sent to Russia, 1845 October 25, 1848 August 5; [7390 F 5] (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Davis, Edwin H., 1845 October 26; [7388 F 77] (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Stellwagen, H. S., regarding asking the Navy Department to defray the expenses of his illness, 1845 November; [7388 F 79] (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - Fory, John C., letter of thanks for Crania aegyptiaca, 1845 November 1; [7388 F 81] (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Roberts, W. Lea, note and enclosed letter of introduction from G.R. Gliddon, 1845 November 4; [7388 F 82] (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - Maclure Alex, Fory, J. C., regarding his Maclure's brother's estate, 1845 November 16-1848 November 23, undated; [7390 F 23] (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - Norman, B. M., requesting Crania aegyptiaca for Dr. Carpenter, 1845 December 1; [7388 F 83] (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - Jarvis, Samuel Farmar, regarding "reconciling the dates of Scripture with the Egyptians," etc., 1845 December 2; [7388 F 84] (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - Wislizenus, A., letter of thanks, 1845 December 3; [7388 F 85] (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - Audubon, Victor G., regarding copying his father's articles, 1845 December 4, 1845 December 18, 1845 December 29; [7388 F 95] (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - See, Charles A., acknowledging receipt of packages, 1845 December 9; [7388 F 87] (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - Ludwig, E. H., regarding books on craniology from Germany, 1845 December 15; [7388 F 90] (Box 1, Folder 101)
  - Wright, F. N., with copy of a letter from Dr. Jones, 1845 December 18; [7388 F 92] (Box 1, Folder 102)
  - Holmes, Francis. S., regarding fossils, etc., 1846 January 6, 1848 June 15; [7389 F 113] (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Audubon, Victor G., regarding his father's writings, 1846 January 7, 1846 January 31, 1846 February 18, 1846 December 21, 1847 January 8; [7389 F 49] (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Blith, George, 1846 January 13; [7389 F 1] (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Jay, John C., 1846 January 16; [7389 F 2] (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Clot-Bey [Antoine Barthelemy Clot], regarding crania of the Turks, 1846 January 21; [7389 F 3] (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Baird, Spencer Fullerton, regarding vaccinations and hybrids among animals, etc., 1846 January 28, 1846 February 16, 1846 September 21; [7389 F 31] (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Gliddon, George R. and W. A. Gliddon and R. K. Haight, regarding marriage, voyage, etc., 1846 January 28-1846 October 6; [7389 F 34] (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Silliman, Benjamin Jr., regarding skulls from a mound in Ohio, 1846 February 2; [7389 F 4] (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Silliman, Benjamin Jr., regarding American Journal of Science, etc., 1846 February 3-1847 August 5; [7389 F 79] (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Norwood, Joseph G., with printed description of fossil fish, 1846 February 16, 1846 February 25; [7389 F 7] (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Nott, Josiah C., acknowledging his appointment as corresponding member of the Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia and regarding Mr. Lyell's visit, 1846 February 23; [7389 F 5] (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Locke, John, regarding Asturias from the blue limestone of Cincinnati, 1846 February 24; [7389 F 6] (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - [McCary], Robert B., inquiring regarding membership in the Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia, 1846 March 2; [7389 F 8] (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Tuomey, M., regarding fossils, 1846 March 15, 1847 February 28; [7389 F 56] (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Parsons, Samuel B., regarding the climate of Florida, 1846 March 18; [7389 F 9] (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Cooper, Joseph B., regarding fossils, Indian relics, and numismatology, 1846 March 19; [7389 F 10] (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Gibbes, Robert W. and Josiah C. Nott, 1846 March 20, 1846 April 4, 1846 June 2, 1846 September 21, 1846 October 30; [7389 F 41] (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Ryan, Charles, letter of thanks, 1846 March 21; [7389 F 11] (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Say, Mrs. L. W., regarding a monument to her husband and a trip through the backwoods, etc., 1846 March 28, 1846 October 11; [7389 F 36] (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Baily, J. W., regarding fossils, origin of natives of America, etc., 1846 April 13, 1847 April 1, 1847 June 27; [7389 F 75] (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Hale, C. S., regarding fossil shells from Alabama, 1846 April 14; [7389 F 12] (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Huffnagle, Charles, regarding crania, 1846 April 14, 1848 January 3, 1848 November 18; [7390 F 21] (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Beck, Theodore Romeyn, regarding the death of Dr. Baker, 1846 April 17; [7389 F 13] (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Markoe, Francis, Jr., regarding the Smithsonian Institution, 1846 April 20-1847 December 30; [7389 F 96] (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Parrish, Isaac, notice from Philadelphia Medical Society regarding Morton's appointment as delegate to National Medical Convention, 1846 April 22; [7389 F 14] (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Haldeman, S. S., regarding Dr. Wilson's gift and hybridity, 1846 April 24, 1846 May 21, 1846 November, 18848 June 1; [7389 F 109] (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Dana, James D., note accompanying his book Zoophytes, 1846 May; [7389 F 15] (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Taylor, Richard C., regarding the purchase of a European cabinet of fossils, 1846 May 17; [7389 F 16] (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Davis, Edwin H., regarding Indian altars found with mound, etc., 1846 May 18; [7389 F 17] (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Haight, Richard K., 1846 May 24, 1846 June 1, 1846 September 4; [7389 F 27] (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Koch, A. C., regarding an echinus, 1846 May 30; [7389 F 18] (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Squier, Ephraim George, regarding the American Ethnological Society and craniology, etc., 1846 June 10-1848 December 28; [7390 F 29] (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Wilson, J. W., regarding skulls, 1846 June 22; [7389 F 19] (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Clay, Joseph, regarding lands in Virginia, 1846 June 23, 1848 February 29; [7389 F 99] (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Rhoades, Ebenezer, regarding his wife's health, 1846 June 23; [7389 F 20] (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Jarvis, Samuel Farmar, regarding the chronology of the Bible and Egypt, 1846 July 2, 1846 September 22, 1846 October 3, 1847 April 10; [7389 F 20] (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Kippist, Richard, regarding contributions to the Linnean Society, and acknowledgement from the Society for a gift, 1846 July 6, 1846 October 15; [7388 F 57, 7389 F 38] (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Hardy, J. F. E., regarding Indian skulls, 1846 July 13; [7389 F 21] (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Peale, T. R., regarding skulls formerly in the Philadelphia museum, 1846 July 14; [7389 F 22] (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Lyell, Charles, regarding fossils given to Mr. Owen, 1846 July 14; [7389 F 23] (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Graff, Charles, letter accompanying wine, 1846 July 18; [7389 F 24] (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Norman, B. M., regarding his wish to be consul to Peru, 1846 July 20, 1846 August 24; [7389 F 25] (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Gray, Asa, mentioning Mr. Agassig, etc., 1846 August 19, 1846 October 13; [7389 F 37] (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Barratt, John P., regarding articles taken from Indian mounds and regarding Negroes, 1846 September 2; [7389 F 26] (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Pickering, Charles, regarding his application for the position of secretary of the Smithsonian Institution, 1846 September 7; [7389 F 28] (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Lee, Alfred B., announcing his examination before the Army Board, 1846 September 8; [7389 F 29] (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - [Boudin], 1846 September 15; [7389 F 30] (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Bateman, Warner M., inquiring regarding the result of this investigation of Negro crania, 1846 September 28; [7389 F 32] (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Dale, John B., regarding Mr. Strain, 1846 October 2; [7389 F 33] (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Gould, P., requesting statistics of homeopathy, 1846 October 7; [7389 F 35] (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Fory, John C., regarding William Maclure's estate, 1846 October 17; [7389 F 39] (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Blanding, William, regarding his nephew Abram, 1846 October 28; [7389 F 40] (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Wilkes, Charles, regarding Dr. Pickering's wish to have his works published in the United States, 1846 November 6; [7389 F 42] (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Ducatel, J. T., letter introducing Dr. Newman, 1846 November 16; [7389 F 43] (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Harden, John M. B., regarding Indian mounds, 1846 November 16; [7389 F 44] (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Ord, G., regarding Mr. Waterton's house, 1846 November 17; [7389 F 45] (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Société Royale des Antiquaires du Nord, regarding his gifts of books, 1846 November 19; [7389 F 46] (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Grant, Robert, letter to accompany a synopsis of an article on hybrids, 1846 December 1; [7389 F 47] (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Wilson, Thomas B., regarding collecting birds, animals, etc. for a natural history collection, 1846 December 9; [7389 F 47.5] (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Bartlett, John R., regarding the American Ethnological Society, 1846 December 21-1848 August 4; [7390 F 4] (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Gibbes, Robert W., regarding fossils, 1847 January 7-1847 December 30; [7389 F 94] (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Troost, Gerard, regarding the origin of the Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia, 1847 January 10; [7389 F 50] (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Wyman, J., 1847 January 10, 1847 July 4, 1847 August 5, 1848 January 1; [7389 F 97] (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Johnston, A. S., 1847 January 13; [7389 F 51] (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Collins, Alfred M., letter thanking Morton for medical attention, 1847 January 14; [7389 F 52] (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - McMurtrie, H., soliciting recommendations, 1847 January 25, 1847 October 9, 1848 October 14; [7390 F 15] (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Maitland, N. C., regarding his sister's certificate of stock, 1847 February 5; [7389 F 53] (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Welcker, George L., regarding James St. Clair Morton's appointment as cadet at West Point, 1847 February 24, 1847 March 6; [7389 F 58] (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Ingersoll, J. R., regarding James St. Clair Morton's appointment as cadet at West Point, 1847 February 25; [7389 F 55] (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Trudeau, James, letter introducing William H. Edwards, 1847 March 2; [7389 F 57] (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Hass, W. D., regarding Indian relics from the mound at Grave Creek, 1847 March 10, 20; [7389 F 60] (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Edwards, William H., regarding engaging Mr. Leavens to collect natural history specimens, 1847 March 11, 1847 March 25, 1847 May 17; [7389 F 68] (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Koeppen, Adolphus S., regarding a gift to the Royal Society of Northern Antiquarians in Copenhagen, 1847 March 27; [7389 F 61] (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Retzius, Anders, regarding crania, 1847 April 3-1848 November 20, undated; [7390 F 22] (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Foster, W. A., regarding Dr. Oakford's situation in Paita, 1847 April 6; [7389 F 62] (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Powel, Samuel, regarding his son's and father's health, 1847 April 10, 1847 May 3; [7389 F 67] (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Dudly, D. W., congratulating Morton on his work on hybridity, 1847 April 15; [7389 F 64] (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Adams, W. G., inquiring about the language of ancient Egyptians, crania, etc., 1847 April 19; [7389 F 65] (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Salisbury, Edward E., letter to accompany the Journal of the American Oriental Society, 1847 April 24; [7389 F 66] (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Abert, J. J., regarding species of birds found by his son, 1847 May 1, 1847 May 17, 1847 May 27; [7389 F 70] (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Carpenter, W. M., regarding Indians, 1847 May 26, 1848 September 8; [7390 F 7] (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - MacCarthy, M. Felix, introducing Francis Rogerson, 1847 May 26; [7389 F 69] (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Nott, Josiah C., regarding Negroes of Mobile and New Orleans, 1847 June 1, 1849 June 27; [7389 F 77] (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Cowper, G., regarding the sickness and death of his aunt, 1847 June 6-1848 October 4; [7390 F 14] (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - McClellan, J. H. B., 1847 June 8; [7389 F 72] (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - [Swaby], John, regarding the ethnology of the American race, 1847 June 13; [7389 F 73] (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Oakford, Samuel J., regarding collecting Indian relics, 1847 June 14, 1847 November 10; [7389 F 89] (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Watson, John, regarding skulls from the East Indies collected by Dr. Mead, 1847 June 15; [7389 F 74] (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Combs, Leslie, regarding crossing the buffalo with domestic cattle, 1847 June 18; [7389 F 75] (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Brophy, Michael, requesting help, 1847 August 2; [7389 F 78] (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Horner, W. E., regarding his services to Mrs. Binney, 1847 August 9; [7389 F 80] (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Hildreth, S. P., regarding fossil wood, 1847 August 19, 1848 March 13; [7389 F 100] (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - Abert, J. W., regarding mineral fossils, etc. from New Mexico, 1847 August 28; [7389 F 81] (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - d'Eichthal, Gustav, regarding the origin of the human race, 1847 August 30; [7389 F 82] (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - Pease, W. H. and Francis Markoe Jr., 1847 September 7/11; [7389 F 83] (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - Gardner, Francis, announcement of the American Oriental Society, 1847 September 9; [7389 F 84] (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - Norman, B. M., regarding his return from Washington, 1847 September 11; [7389 F 85] (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - Culbertson, S. D., letter accompanying some skulls, 1847 September 16; [7389 F 86] (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - Blanding, William, regarding his nephew Abram, 1847 September 18, 1848 March 27; [7389 F 103] (Box 2, Folder 99)
  - London British Museum, unknown author, 1847 October 2; [7389 F 87] (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - Report from Military Academy, 1847 October 19-1848 December 18; [7390 F 25] (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - Page, Thomas L., mentioning the death of Dr. Houstoun, 1847 October 31; [7389 F 88] (Box 2, Folder 102)
  - Robertson, F. M., inquiring about insane asylums, 1847 November 23; [7389 F 90] (Box 2, Folder 103)
  - Brydges, H. J. S., regarding Peale's painting of Waterton, 1847 November 24; [7389 F 91] (Box 2, Folder 104)
  - Lieber, J. O. M., regarding the distribution of pamphlets, 1847 November 29; [7389 F 92] (Box 2, Folder 105)
  - Foster, W. A., regarding crania from Peru (unfinished), 1847 December 1; [7389 F 93] (Box 2, Folder 106)
  - Holmes, R. S., regarding a mummified head from Buena Vista, 1847 December 16; [7389 F 95] (Box 2, Folder 107)
  - Gliddon, George R., regarding his lecture tour and regarding his brother, 1848 January 9, 1848 February 3, 1848 April 7, 1848 May 15; [7390 F 1] (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Graham, James, thanking Morton for his professional services, 1848 January 19; [7389 F 98] (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Gibbes, Robert W., regarding paleontology, 1848 February 18-1849 February 22; [7390 F 38] (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Wislizenus, A., regarding books for Dr. Engelman, 1848 March 8, 1848 May 6; [7389 F 108] (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Swift, Edward, letter to accompany specimens of mineral, 1848 March 13; [7389 F 101] (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Storer, D. Humphrey, introducing Dr. Stone, 1848 April 2; [7389 F 104] (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Van Amringe, W. F., regarding the natural history of man, 1848 April 10-1848 August 31; [7390 F 58] (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Nicholson, C., letter to accompany skulls from Australia, 1848 April 11; [7389 F 105] (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Richards, B. W., regarding a letter from van Amringe, 1848 April 11; [7389 F 106] (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Hoyt, Otis, regarding W.H. Pease, 1848 May 4; [7389 F 107] (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Shipman, A. B., announcing his election as honorary member of the North Western Academy of Natural and Medical Sciences, 1848 June 8; [7389 F 110] (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Engelmann, George, mentioning Dr. Wislizenus and Dr. Holmes, 1848 June 9; [7389 F 111] (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Cohen, Joshua J., inquiring regarding Dr. Gliddon, 1848 June 11; [7389 F 112] (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Hodgson, William B., regarding paleontology, Egyptology, etc., 1848 June 26, 1848 June 30, 1848 June 25, 1848 March 23; [7389 F 102] (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Johnson, W. R., regarding his resignation as secretary of the Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia, 1848 July 1; [7390 F 2] (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Gibbes, Lewis R., mentioning the American Association for Promoting Science, 1848 July 6; [7390 F 3] (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Harris, A. C., letter accompanying plates, 1848 August 21; [7390 F 6] (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Redfield, William C., regarding the American Association of the Advancement of Science, 1848 September 11; [7390 F 8] (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Fussell, Edwin, regarding Dr. Alter's death, 1848 September 12; [7390 F 9] (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Hubbard, J. S., regarding his paper for the American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1848 September 14; [7390 F 10] (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Millington, John, with enclosed letter for Benjamin Silliman, Jr., 1848 September 18; [7390 F 11] (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Kern, Richard H., regarding his departure from Philadelphia, 1848 September 20; [7390 F 12] (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Morris, Jacob G., mentioning Professor August Zeune, 1848 September 21; [7390 F 13] (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Clayton, Charles M., regarding his health, 1848 October 20; [7390 F 16] (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Barratt, John P., Letter accompanying Indian goods, etc., 1848 October 25; [7390 F 17] (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Monro, Alex, introducing Dr. Nasmyth and telling Morton of Dr. Lister's death, 1848 October 30; [7390 F 18] (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Say, Mrs. Lucy W., regarding Maclure's estate, 1848 November 9; [7390 F 19] (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Hulse, Isaac, regarding an Indian skull from Alabama, 1848 November 15; [7390 F 20] (Box 3, Folder 28)